Guide to the Central Washington University Faculty Papers of Helen Michaelson 1939-1942>
Central Washington University Archives and Special Collections
Central Washington University Faculty Papers, Helen Michaelson
1939-1942
Central Washington University Archives and Special Collections 400 E University Way Ellensburg, WA 98926 (509) 963-1717 http://www.lib.cwu.edu/Archives-Special-Collections archives@cwu.edu
FP-0038
Helen Michaelson
10 rolls of home movies taken by Helen Michaelson
Helen Michaelson
Helen M. Michaelson was associate professor of home economics at Central Washington State College from 1937 until her retirement in 1970. She earned a master’s degree at the University of Washington. Extremely active in her profession, she developed a modern program in home economics to train teachers for the public schools.
This collection of home movies from the 1940’s includes footage from a trip to China in 1940 and trips to the Grand Canyon and the Canadian Rockies as well as scenes from around the Central Washington University campus and Kittitas County from the 1940’s.
One series, films in box in original order.
These films have been digitized and the files are available for viewing in the reading room
Open ot the public
Films had been given to Barbara Foster by Helen Michaelson
Materials Donated by Barbara Foster
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the online catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search the catalog using these headings.
Michaelson, Helen--Archives
Central Washington University; China
Moving Images; Colleges and Universities; Washington (State)
- 8mm Projector Keystone sixty, 1940 (Box 1)
- 8mm film Helen and Elizabeth, 1939 (Box-folder 1-1)
- 8mm film Grand Canyon, 1939 (Box-folder 1-2)
- 8mm film Canadian Rockies, 1939 (Box-folder 1-3)
- 8mm film Home Econ. Club, 1939 (Box-folder 1-4)
- 8mm film Swauk Lumbering, 1940 (Box-folder 1-5)
- 8mm film Shanghai, 1940 (Box-folder 1-6)
- 8mm film Peking 1, 1940 (Box-folder 1-7)
- 8mm film Peking 2, 1940 (Box-folder 1-8)
- 8mm film Campus, 1939 (Box-folder 1-9)
- 8mm film Louise and Earl's wedding, 1942 (Box-folder 1-10)